# **THAMIZHARASAN**

#### CONTACT



No.2/278, Small Street, Thumbikulam, Thiruttani



(**1**) +91-7418616486



thamizhsarasan@gmail.com

### **CORE QUALIFICATIONS**

AWS & DevOps Engineer having a foundation in fundamentals of cloud computing with 4 years of hands-on experience in architecting/ automating and optimizing mission-critical deployments over large infrastructure. Proficient with Configuration Management tools, and in developing CI/CD pipelines.

#### **LANGUAGES**

**English:** First Language

Tamil:

Proficient

Seeking a position to utilise my skills and abilities in your organization and exhibiting my skills with almost sincerity & dedication, work for the growth of the organisation along with mine while being resourceful, innovative, and flexible.

#### **EDUCATION**

2016

**B.E Electronics & Instrumentation Engineering (E.I.E)** Sri Sairam Engineering College, Chennai

- Year of Study: 2012-2016
- AICTE & NBA Approved.
- ISO 9001:2015 Certified Institution
- Affiliated to Anna University

**Higher Secondary (HSC)** Tamilnadu State board

Percentage: 70.16

2010

SECONDARY EDUCATION (SSLC) Tamilnadu State board.

Percentage: 75.6

#### **EXPERIENCE**

June 2019 - Current

AWS and DevOps Engineer Appteq IT solutions, Chennai, INDIA **ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES:** 

- Good Experience with Version Control System such as Git, Administrating source code management by GitHub repository
- Created branches, tags and handled merge conflict using Git merge
- Experience on implementing CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins and running jobs on slave machine using Master Slave Connection.
- Used Apache Maven Project management tool POM file to automate the build process in Jenkins to manage project libraries, compiling, preparing war file and deploying in Apache Tomcat.
- Automated build jobs and deployment process with Jenkins.
- Built and deployed Docker containers for implementing micro services architecture from monolithic architecture.
- Basic experience on Ansible playbooks and ad hoc commands. Created Ansible-Roles and used Ansible-Vault on configuration
- Experience in the provisioning Cloud Infrastructure using Amazon Web Services.
- Created Three-tier architecture in AWS using services like EC2, S3, EFS, lambda, IAM, Load Balancer, Auto Scaling, VPC, Route 53, Cloud Front, Cloud Watch, RDS.
- Created S3 buckets and S3 life cycle management for old data's and logs. Also adding EBS and EFS Whenever required.

- Experience on VPC peering & NAT Gateway for application servers hosted on private subnets.
- Basic knowledge in Kubernetes orchestration.
- Experience on CI/ CD workflow using Code Deploy & Code Pipeline.
- Written Terraform code for building Cloud Infrastructure.
   Automated builds workflow using terraform. Knowledge on Cloud Formation.
- Knowledge on Application Monitoring Tools like Prometheus, CloudWatch on AWS
- Knowledge on Log Monitoring Tools like New relic, CloudTrail on AWS
- Hands-on knowledge on SonarQube for code quality check.
- Good Experience in Operating systems like Windows & Linux (Red Hat) commands.
- Good knowledge in Infrastructure maintenance and have good troubleshooting skills.
- Worked in Agile DevOps enabling working environment using Atlassian tools JIRA to track issues and change Management

November 2017 - May 2018

## **Production Engineer** *Technocraft Private. Ltd,* Chennai, INDIA ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES:

- PPAP- Document preparation: It is the approval form that consists
  of thecontrol plan, FMEA, PSW, MSA, SPC, process audit and
  process flow diagram. I am responsible for clearing all these
  documents get the final approval.
- Drawing Study, Process sequence determination, manufacturing feasibility study, Make or Buy decision, Preparing - Routing List, Process flow, Process Matrix & Control Plan

#### TECHNICAL SKILL SET

- AWS Services: EC2, S3, EFS, lambda, IAM, Load Balancer, Auto Scaling, VPC, Route 53, CloudFront, Cloud Watch, RDS, SQS, SNS, Code Deploy & Code Pipeline.
- DEVOPS Tools: Git, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Terraform, AppDynamics, Newrelic, Kubernetes.
- Operating System: Windows, Linux.
- Telnet Tools: Git Bash, PuTTY, PuTTYgen, Pageant, WinSCP.

#### PERSONAL DATA

Father's Name: R Sankaran

Gender: Male.

Marital Status: Single.

Date of Birth: 10th April,1995.

Nationality: Indian. Mother Tongue: Tamil. PAN:BKAPT1259D

#### **DECLARATION**

I hereby solemnly affirm that, all the details provided above are true to the best of my knowledge.

Yours faithfully, (Thamizharasan. s)